<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Polish National Parks</string>
    <string name="app_info">
    This is Polish National Parks Android app\n
    made by: Dominik Krzemiński\n
    date:12-13.03.16\n
    It is simple application showing info about all 23 Polish National Parks. Information taken from
        wikipedia.org. All pictures taken from wikipedia as well or free reusable license resources.
        \n---\nInspired by Study Jam Android - GDG Warsaw.
    </string>
    <string name="park1"> Babiogorski NP </string>
    <string name="park2"> Bialowieski NP </string>
    <string name="park3"> Biebrzanski NP </string>
    <string name="park4"> Bieszczadzki NP </string>
    <string name="park5"> Borow Tucholskich NP </string>
    <string name="park6"> Drawienski NP </string>
    <string name="park7"> Gorczanski NP </string>
    <string name="park8"> Kampinoski NP </string>
    <string name="park9"> Karkonoski NP </string>
    <string name="park10"> Magurski NP </string>
    <string name="park11"> Narwianski NP </string>
    <string name="park12"> Ojcowski NP </string>
    <string name="park13"> Pieninski NP </string>
    <string name="park14"> Poleski NP </string>
    <string name="park15"> Roztoczanski NP </string>
    <string name="park16"> Slowinski NP </string>
    <string name="park17"> Stolowe Mountains NP </string>
    <string name="park18"> Swietokrzyski NP </string>
    <string name="park19"> Tatrzanski NP </string>
    <string name="park20"> Ujscie Warty NP </string>
    <string name="park21"> Wielkopolski NP </string>
    <string name="park22"> Wigierski NP </string>
    <string name="park23"> Wolinski NP </string>
    <string name="park1_info"> It is ocated in the southern part of the country, in Lesser Poland Voivodeship, on the border with Slovakia. The Park has its headquarters in the village of Zawoja. The park covers an area of 33.92 square kilometres (13.10 sq mi), of which forests occupy 31.98 km2 (12.35 sq mi). </string>
    <string name="park2_info"> It is a National Park in Podlaskie Voivodeship, in Eastern Poland adjacent with the border with Belarus. The total area of the park is 152.2 square kilometres (58.8 sq mi). It is located 62 km (39 mi) southeast of Białystok (Poland).  </string>
    <string name="park3_info"> The largest of Poland’s 23 National Parks, the Biebrza National Park was created on September 9, 1993. Its total area is 592.23 km2 (228.66 sq mi), of which forests cover 155.47 km², fields and meadows covering 181.82 km² and marshes with an area of 254.94 km².</string>
    <string name="park4_info"> Bieszczadzki NP is the third largest National Park in Poland, located in Subcarpathian Voivodeship in the extreme south-east corner of the country, bordering Slovakia and Ukraine. </string>
    <string name="park5_info"> It covers an area of 46.13 square kilometres (17.81 sq mi) of forests, lakes, meadows and peatlands. The Park is located in the northern part of Poland, in Chojnice County in Pomeranian Voivodeship, in the heart of the Tuchola Forest, the largest woodland in Poland. It is surrounded by a larger protected area called Zaborski Landscape Park. The Park forms the core of the Tuchola Forest Biosphere Reserve, designated by UNESCO in 2010. </string>
    <string name="park6_info">  The park is a part of the huge Drawsko Forest (Puszcza Drawska), which lies on the vast Drawsko Plain. It takes its name from the River Drawa. It was created in 1990 and initially covered 86.91 km². </string>
    <string name="park7_info">  It covers central and northeastern parts of the Gorce Mountains, which are part of the Western Beskids (at the western end of the Carpathian range). The first steps to protect this land go back to 1927, when a forest reserve was set up on land owned by Count Ludwik Wodzicki of Poręba Wielka. The National Park was created in 1981, then covering 23.9 square kilometres. Today, the area of the park has grown to 70.3 km2 (27.1 sq mi), of which 65.91 km² is forested.  </string>
    <string name="park8_info">  National Park in east-central Poland, in Masovian Voivodeship, on the north-west outskirts of Warsaw. It has a sister park agreement with Indiana Dunes National Lakeshore, Indiana, United States. The idea of creating a park here appeared for the first time in the 1920s. In the 1930s the first forest reserves were opened: Granica, Sieraków and Zamczysko. Today, these reserves are much larger and are strictly protected. </string>
    <string name="park9_info"> The park is located in Lower Silesian Voivodeship, in the highest part of the Sudetes. It was created in 1959 to cover an area of 55.10 km². Today it is slightly larger at 55.76 km2 (21.53 sq mi), of which 17.18 km² is strictly protected. The majority of the park area, around 33.80 km², consists of forests. In 1992 Karkonosze National Park, together with the neighbouring Czech National Park, became part of the Krkonose / Karkonosze biosphere reserve under UNESCO’s Man and the Biosphere (MaB) programme </string>
    <string name="park10_info"> It is a National Park located in the south-east of Poland, close to Slovakia, on the boundary of Lesser Poland Voivodeship and Subcarpathian Voivodeship. It covers the main part of the upper basin of the Wisłoka river. When the Park was created in 1995 it covered 199.62 km², although it is now only 194.39 km2 (75.05 sq mi), of which 185.31 km² is forest. The Park takes its name from the massif known as Magura Wątkowska, after Wątkowa, its highest peak. Magura is also the name of the second-highest peak of this massif.</string>
    <string name="park11_info"> The park covers the Upper Narew Valley, a swampy area between the towns of Suraz and Rzedziany. Around 90% of Park’s area are either swamps or waters with the Narew as the main river, which splits in the area into many river beds, but also numerous smaller rivers, such as Liza, Szeroka Struga, Awissa, Kurówka, Kowalówka, Turośnianka and Czaplinianka. The Park’s landscape is predominantly made up by many varieties of marshes, reed beds, and there are also meadows and forests. The Narew Valley is a haven for birds - there are 179 species of them, including those unique for the area. Mammals are represented by around 40 species, among them some elk and otter as well as numerous beavers - around 260 of them. The Park’s waters are full of fish - 22 species - as well as amphibians. The Park is a wetland site protected under the Ramsar convention. </string>
    <string name="park12_info"> It is Poland\'s smallest national park, with an original area of 14.40 square kilometers (5.56 sq mi), since expanded to 21.46 km2 (8.29 sq mi). Of this area, 15.28 km2 (5.90 sq mi) is forested and 2.51 km2 (0.97 sq mi) is strictly protected. The park is approximately 16 kilometers (10 mi) north of Kraków, in the Jurassic Kraków-Częstochowa Upland.</string>
    <string name="park13_info"> It is a protected area located in the heart of Pieniny Mountains in the southernmost part of Poland. Administratively, the Park lies in the Lesser Poland Voivodeship on the border with Slovakia. Its head office is in Krościenko nad Dunajcem. The Pieniny mountain chain is divided into three ranges: Pieniny Spiskie, Małe Pieniny and the Pieniny Właściwe range where the Park is located. The Park’s area is 23.46 square kilometres (9.06 sq mi), of which 13.11 km² is forested. One-third (7.5 km²) is strictly protected. </string>
    <string name="park14_info">  Created in 1990 over an area of 48.13 square kilometres, it covers a number of former peat-bog preserves: Durne Bagno, Jezioro Moszne, Jezioro Długie, Torfowisko Orłowskie. In 1994 its size was augmented by the addition of Bagno Bubnów, a swampy terrain adjacent to the park. Currently, the park occupies 97.62 km2 (37.69 sq mi), of which forests make up 47.8 km², and water and wastelands 20.9 km². The idea of creating a National Park in the Polish part of Polesie first appeared in 1959. Over the following years a few preserves were organized here, and in 1982 the government announced the creation of Poleski Park Krajobrazowy (Polesie Landscape Park). Currently, even though Polesie’s infrastructure is quite well developed, it is rarely visited by tourists. In the village of Załucze Stare there is a cultural center with a museum. </string>
    <string name="park15_info"> The beginnings of nature protection in the region date back to 1934, when the Bukowa Góra Preserve was created (now it is a strictly protected area). In 1938, for the first time in Poland, a bill was issued which stated that prey birds on the area of the Zamoyski family estate were protected. The Park itself was created from State Forests of Districts of Kosobudy and Zwierzyniec, which had belonged to the Zamoyski family estate. The Park is located in a picturesque Roztocze Środkowe Region, in the upper Wieprz river valley.  </string>
    <string name="park16_info">  It is situated on the Baltic coast, between Łeba and Rowy. The northern boundary of the park consists of 32.5 kilometres (20.2 mi) of coastline. In the past, the park\'s area was a Baltic Sea bay. The sea\'s activity, however, created sand dunes which in the course of time separated the bay from the Baltic Sea. </string>
    <string name="park17_info">The Stołowe Mountains landscape started to form 70 million years ago. The range’s unique shape is a result of hundreds of thousands of years of erosion. There are several notable rock formations, among them Kwoka ("Hen"), Wielblad ("Camel") and Glowa wielkoluda ("Giant’s head"). Also, there is a sophisticated system of corridors which creates rock labyrinths.Currently plant life is mostly made up of spruce, which was introduced to the area on the turn of the 19th century to replace pristine beech and fir forests, which had been cut. </string>
    <string name="park18_info">  It covers the highest ridge of the Świętokrzyskie (Holy Cross) Mountains – the Łysogory – with its two highest peaks: Łysica at 612 metres (2,008 ft) and Łysa Góra ("Bald Mountain") at 595 m (1,952 ft). It also covers the eastern part of the Klonowski Ridge and part of the Pokrzywianski Ridge. The Park has its headquarters in Bodzentyn. </string>
    <string name="park19_info"> It is a National Park located in the Tatra Mountains in Tatra County, in the Lesser Poland Voivodeship—Małopolska region, in central-southern Poland bordering on northern Slovakia.  The Park has its headquarters in the town of Zakopane. The National Park covers one of the two Alpine mountain ranges in Poland. The Polish Tatra range, which is a part of the Western Carpathian Mountains, is divided into two sections: the High Tatras (Tatry Wysokie) and the Western Tatras (Tatry Zachodnie). The landscape consists of sharp-edged peaks and hollows with numerous rock formations.  The highest peak in Poland, Rysy (2,499 metres (8,199 ft) AMSL), is located here.</string>
    <string name="park20_info">  The name Ujście Warty means "mouth of the Warta" – the Polish word ujście also being used for the termination of a river at another river or lake rather than the sea.The Park was created on the area of the former Słońsk Nature Reserve, which had existed since 1977, and parts of the Ujście Warty Landscape Park. The ground here is swampy and muddy, which makes it a haven for birds. This is why the former Słońsk preserve, which is now part of the Park, was in 1984 covered by the Ramsar Convention, which purpose is to protect such areas.</string>
    <string name="park21_info"> It is a National Park within the Wielkopolska (Greater Poland) region of west-central Poland, approximately 15 km (9 mi) south of the regional capital, Poznań. Together with the protective zone around it, it includes part of the Poznań Lakeland (Pojezierze Poznańskie) and parts of Poznań’s Warta Gorge (Poznański Przełom Warty).The Park has its headquarters in the village of Jeziory. </string>
    <string name="park22_info"> The Park was created on January 1, 1989, on an area of 149.56 km2. Today it is slightly larger at 150.86 km2 (58.25 sq mi), of which 94.64 km2 is forest, 29.08 km2 is waters and 27.14 km2 other types of land, mostly agricultural. Strictly protected zones account for 6.23 km2, including 2.83 km2 of woods. The Park has its headquarters in the town of Suwałki.The Park’s landscape was to a large extent shaped by a glacier which covered this region around 12,000 years ago. The glacier, while slowly receding to the North, formed valleys, many of which are filled with water in the form of lakes.  </string>
    <string name="park23_info">It was established on 3 March 1960 and covers an area of 109.37 square kilometres (42.23 sq mi). The Park has its headquarters in the town of Międzyzdroje.The Park contains a number of species of flora and fauna. Its attractions include the sea cliffs of Gosań and Kawcza Góra, and a wisent (European bison) sanctuary </string>
    <string name="park1_url"> http://www.bgpn.pl/</string>
    <string name="park2_url"> http://www.bpn.com.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park3_url"> http://www.biebrza.org.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park4_url"> https://www.bdpn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park5_url"> http://www.pnbt.com.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park6_url"> http://dpn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park7_url"> http://www.gorczanskipark.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park8_url"> https://www.kampinoski-pn.gov.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park9_url"> http://kpnmab.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park10_url"> http://www.magurskipn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park11_url"> http://www.npn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park12_url"> http://www.ojcow.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park13_url"> http://www.pieninypn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park14_url"> http://www2.poleskipn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park15_url"> http://roztoczanskipn.pl </string>
    <string name="park16_url"> http://slowinskipn.pl/</string>
    <string name="park17_url"> http://www.pngs.com.pl/</string>
    <string name="park18_url"> http://www.swietokrzyskipn.org.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park19_url"> http://tpn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park20_url"> http://www.pnujsciewarty.gov.pl/english.htm </string>
    <string name="park21_url"> http://www.wielkopolskipn.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park22_url"> http://www.wigry.win.pl/ </string>
    <string name="park23_url"> http://www.wolinpn.pl/ </string>

</resources>
